A racing second hand, shining shooting stars!
عقرب دقائق مسرِع، شهب لامعة
Conan's logic is good medicine for hearts tired by modern society!
استنتاجات كونان دواء ممتاز للقلوب !المُثقلة بالمجتمع الحديث
Today is the Dracula solution! The trick is exposed before sunrise!
اليوم ختام قضيّة دراكولا! تنكشف حقيقة !الحيلة قبل طلوع الشمس
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
The old man was hired by Mr. Dorakura, owner of Dracula Manor,
،تلقّى العمّ طلب تحقيق من السيّد دوراكورا ،مالك قصر دراكولا
That night, someone killed Mr. Dorakura with a stake to the heart,
في تلك الليلة، قتل أحدهم السيّد دوراكورا طعناً
in his completely-locked study room!
بوتد في قلبه داخل مكتبه المقفل تماماً
To get to the study, one would have to pass through the living room,
للوصول للمكتب، على المرء المرور بغرفة المعيشة
where everyone was at the time!
حيث تواجدنا وقتها
Breaking in from outside was also impossible!
كان التسلّل من الخارج مستحيلاً أيضاً
Did the killer fly through the air, like a vampire?!
أيمكن أنّ القاتل طار في السماء حقّاً مثل مصّاص دماء؟
My, what a farce that was.
يا إلهي، كانت مسرحيّةً بحقّ
That's the roof above the collection room...
ذاك سقف غرفة المقتنيات
What are those imprints in the snow?
ما تلك الآثار على الثلج؟
Wait a minute!
انتظر
The collection room didn't smell like oil paint after the incident!
لم تكن هناك رائحة طلاء زيتيّ عندما أتيتُ لغرفة المقتنيات بعد وقوع الجريمة
Does that mean...
...مما يعني
Huh?! It doesn't smell!
!ماذا؟ لا رائحة
Hey, you!
!أنت
What're you doing?
ما الذي تفعله؟
Nothing!
!لا شيء
Was that stake not the source of the smell?
لم يكن ذاك الوتد مصدر الرائحة؟
Let's first organize what we know about the incident.
لنقم بتحليل الجريمة
First, at around 8:30, Mr. Dorakura went to the study
بدايةً، توجّه السيّد دوراكورا لمكتبه عند قرابة الثامنة والنصف
and Tadokoro-san, Ran, and Conan went to the collection room
بينما ذهب تادوكورو-سان وران وكونان لغرفة المقتنيات
to get a film.
لجلب فيلم
At that time, the stake used as the murder weapon was still there.
في ذاك الوقت، كان الوتد المستعمل في الجريمة لا يزال موجوداً
In other words, the killer stole the stake after that.
أي أنّ القاتل سرقه بعد ذلك
Moreover, Ran confirmed that all the windows in the collection room
كما تحقّقت ران من كون النوافذ في غرفة المقتنيات
had been locked from the inside.
مقفلة من الداخل جميعها
In short, the only way into the room was from the living room.
فكان الطريق الوحيد للغرفة هو عبر غرفة المعيشة
Next, Tadokoro-san went to the study to deliver the wine and movie.
تالياً، ذهب تادوكورو-سان للمكتب لتوصيل النبيذ والفيلم
Yes. At around 8:50, I left the wine and film and left the study.
،أجل، كان ذلك عند قرابة الثامنة وخمسين دقيقة تركتُ الفيلم والنبيذ وغادرت المكتب
Huh?
ماذا؟
The wine bottle's seal hasn't been broken.
لم يُنزع غطاء قنّينة النبيذ
Did anything seem odd about Mr. Dorakura then?
هل رأيتَ أمراً غريباً على السيّد دوراكورا وقتها؟
No, not really.
كلا، لا شيء
You returned to the living room shortly after 9:00,
رجعتَ لغرفة المعيشة بعد التاسعة بقليل
then left to make sure that everything was locked up.
ثمّ غادرت للتحقّق من أقفال البيت
Yes. I believe I returned ten minutes afterward.
نعم، أظنّني رجعتُ بعد 10 دقائق
The snow had already stopped by then.
كان هطول الثلج قد توقّف وقتها
Shortly after, his wife retired to her room upstairs.
بعد ذلك بقليل، رجعت الزوجة لغرفتها في الطابق العلويّ
Around 9:15, I'd say?
كان ذلك عند قرابة التاسعة والربع
And then she came down when the body was found around midnight.
ثمّ نزلت عند منتصف الليل عندما عُثر على الجثّة
In short, she has no alibi for that period of time.
أي أنّها لم تملك حجّة غياب لتلك الفترة
Hamura-san.
،هامورا-سان
You left the living room the same time she did, to go to the library.
غادرتَ غرفة المعيشة معها وذهبتَ للمكتبة
Yes. I returned to the living room at about 10:30.
أجل، رجعتُ لغرفة المعيشة عند العاشرة والنصف تقريباً
Which means I have no alibi for that period of time.
مما يعني أنّ لا حجّة غياب لي لتلك الفترة
You had the opportunity to steal the stake from the collection room.
كنتَ تملك فرصة سرقة الوتد من غرفة المقتنيات
Doi-san. Right after Hamura-san returned to the living room,
دوري-سان، بعدما رجع هامورا-سان لغرفة المعيشة
you went to the restroom.
ذهبت للحمّام من فورك
You were gone about twenty minutes, wouldn't you say?
غبتَ لعشرين دقيقة تقريباً، صحيح؟
Y-Yes.
أ-أجل
Twenty minutes is enough time to commit the murder.
ذلك وقتٌ كافٍ لارتكاب الجريمة
But I never went to the collection room.
لكنّي لم أذهب لغرفة المقتنيات
Yeah! Doi-san only went to the bathroom!
صحيح، ذهب دوري-سان للحمّام فحسب
He even bumped into Hamura-san on his way!
فقد اصطدم بهامورا-سان في طريقه وقتها
That's right! I didn't think of that!
!فهمت! كانت تلك الحركة ممكنة
Hamura-san. Perhaps you secretly had the stake when that happened?
هامورا-سان، لعلّك كنت تخفي الوتد معك آنذاك؟
And then Doi-san pretended to bump into you and took it.
وتظاهر دوري-سان بالاصطدام بك وأخذه
Quit joking around! Why would I need to kill Dorakura-sensei?!
!لا تعبث معي! لمَ أقتل دوراكورا سينسي؟
What's this?
ما هذا؟
T-That's...
...إ-إنّه
'Call of Darkness', by Nakajima Yoshihiko
"نداء الظلام" ناكاجيما يوشيهيكو
These aren't Mr. Dorakura's manuscripts...
هذه... ليست نصوص السيّد دوراكورا
Could they be novels submitted to Doi-san's magazine by readers?
قد تكون روايات أُرسلت لمجلّة دوري-سان من قِبل القرّاء
See, it says "Horror Times" on the envelope.
انظر، توجد "هورور تايمز" على المظروف
Come to think of it, I have heard an odd rumor,
بذكر ذلك، سمعتُ شائعةً غريبة
from my university's Horror Novel Association,
من رابطة روايات الرعب لجامعتي
that novels submitted to the Horror Times
الروايات التي تُرسل لهورور تايمز
wound up being plagiarized by Dorakura.
تتعرّض للانتحال من قبل دوراكورا
Plagiarized?
للانتحال؟
Don't tell me you were involved with this too, Editor-in-Chief?
أيمكن أنّك متورّط في هذا أيضاً يا رئيس التحرير؟
W-What makes you think--
...ما-ما الذي يجعلك
In that case, we can compare Dorakura's manuscripts on this PC
في تلك الحالة، يمكننا مقارنة نصوص السيّد دوراكورا
with these submitted novels.
بهذه الروايات المُرسلة عبر هذا الحاسوب
T-That's...
...ذ-ذلك
Doi-san.
دوري-سان
It'd be in your best interest to come clean while you still can.
سيكون من صالحك الاعتراف بينما تملك الفرصة
Dorakura... His talent had been dried up for years now.
...إنّه
About seven years ago,
،منذ قرابة سبعة أعوام
I failed in the stock market and found myself in incredible debt.
فشلتُ في سوق الأسهم وحملتُ ديوناً ثقيلة
Dorakura offered to take over my debt if I would leak novels to him.
عرض عليّ دوراكورا تحمّل ديوني مقابل أن أسرّب الروايات له
So, you murdered him to dissolve your relationship, then?
قتلتَه لأنّك أردتَ محو علاقتكما إذاً؟
N-No!
!كـ-كلا
But you have a motive!
!لكن لديك الدافع
If it's motives you want, Tadokoro-kun has one, too!
،إذا كان الموضوع هو الدافع !فلدى تادوكورو-كن دافع بدوره
He was Dorakura's ghostwriter!
!كان الكاتب الخفيّ لدوراكورا
Ghostwriter?!
الكاتب الخفيّ؟
It was five years ago.
كان الأمر قبل خمسة أعوام
No longer able to endure leaking him novels submitted to me,
لم أستطع تحمّل تسريب الروايات المرسلة لي باستمرار
I introduced him to Tadokoro-kun,
فعرّفتُه على تادوكورو-كن
who I learned of through literary magazines.
الذي قرأتُ عنه في مجلّة أدبية
Come to think of it,
...صحيح
didn't Mr. Dorakura start publishing fantasy works five years ago?
ألم يعلن السيّد دوراكورا عن بدء كتابته لأعمال خيال قبل خمسة أعوام؟
Tadokoro-kun wrote them.
كان تادوكورو-كن مؤلّفها
Is this true, Tadokoro-san?!
أذلك صحيح يا تادوكورو-سان؟
It's true.
إنّها الحقيقة
But I don't bear a grudge against him for it.
لكنّي لا أضمر له أيّ ضغينة على ذلك
Even if I did, there's a reason I couldn't kill him!
وإن أضمرت، فهناك سبب يردعني عن قتله
A reason you couldn't kill him?
سبب يردعك عن قتله؟
I have a sister named Kaori, who's ten years younger than me.
لديّ شقيقة تُدعى كاوري تصغرني بعشرة أعوام
She was born with a slightly-faulty heart,
وُلِدت بقلب ضعيف لحدٍّ ما
and as our parents died when she was young,
،وبما أنّ والدينا تُوفيا باكراً
I wasn't able to get her decent medical help.
لم أستطع توفير مساعدة طبيّة كافية لها
But, thanks to Dorakura-sensei, she's now in a hospital in Tokyo.
لكنّها نزيلةٌ في مشفى في طوكيو الآن بفضل دوراكورا سينسي
He offered to pay Kaori's medical and hospital fees
عرض سينسي أن يدفع تكاليف العلاج والمشفى لكاوري إلى أن يتمّ تسريحها
if I became his ghostwriter.
مقابل أن أصبح كاتبه الخفيّ
So, killing Mr. Dorakura would cut off your sister's treatment...
...قتل السيّد دوراكورا سينهي علاج شقيقتك إذاً
Yes.
نعم
Mr. Dorakura sure was one horrible man.
لكن كان السيّد دوراكورا شخصاً فظيعاً بحقّ
A true vampire.
كمصّاص دماء فعليّاً
Even if the victim was as merciless as a vampire, murder is murder!
حتّى لو كان الضحيّة عديم شفقة مثل !مصّاص دماء، يبقى القتل قتلاً
It can't be forgiven.
لا يمكن الصفح عنه
I guess, unless Hamura-san worked with one of the other two,
في حال عدم تعاون هامورا-سان مع الزوجة أو دوي-سان
the murder would've been impossible.
فستستحيل الجريمة بالفعل
But, the only way to get to the only corridor is from the living room.
لكن، السبيل الوحيد للوصول لممرّ المكتب هو عبر غرفة المعيشة
It'd be impossible to sneak past us all.
يستحيل أن يتسلّل أمامنا
Even if it was possible, the study room was locked from the inside.
وحتّى إذا فعل، كان باب المكتب مقفلاً من الداخل
The door had a rubber seal, so outside tricks would be impossible.
للباب حاجز مطاطيّ أيضاً، فلا يمكن تنفيذ حيل من الخارج
And, if the window was used to enter and exit,
،وإذا دخل وخرج من النافذة
only the snow in front of the window had footprints.
فلا آثار إلّا على الثلج أمامها مباشرةً
The weapon was the wooden stake in the collection room,
كان السلاح هو الوتد الخشبيّ في غرفة المقتنيات
so the killer was someone in Dracula Manor tonight.
ما يعني أنّ القاتل كان أحد المتواجدين في قصر دراكولا الليلة
Wait! Why did the person kill him with the stake?
انتظر، لمَ قتله المجرم بالوتد؟
That limited the suspects to those inside the building.
قلّص ذلك قائمة المشتبه بهم للمتواجدين في المنزل
That would be very bad for the killer!
هذا يضرّ كثيراً بالقاتل
Yet... why did they dare to use that weapon?
مع ذلك... لمَ تعمّد القاتل استعمال ذاك السلاح؟
Could it be that...
...أيمكن
I knew it! There's a slight smell of oil paint left!
كنتُ أعرف، تبقّت رائحة طلاء زيتيّ طفيفة
The windows were locked from the inside.
كانت النوافذ مقفلةً من الداخل
The small ventilation windows have spring stoppers...
لنوافذ التهوية الصغيرة سدّادات ارتداديّة
The twig piece I found on the floor under the window...
...طرف الغصين الذي وجدتُه أسفل النافذة
And the strange imprints in the snow on the roof above the window...
والآثار الغريبة على الثلج في السطح فوق النافذة
There's gotta be a connection! What is it?!
...لا بدّ من وجود صلةٍ بينها! صلة ما
That's it! So, that's the deal!
!فهمت! هكذا إذاً
What's this plastic bag?
ما هذا الكيس البلاستيكي؟
This is...
...هذا
There's gotta be a secret passageway here somewhere!
!لا بدّ من وجود معبر سريّ هنا
There's nothing of the sort!
!لا شيء كذاك
I have a good idea who's behind this.
كوّنتُ صورةً للفاعل
But there's still a big mystery left!
لكن لا يزال هناك لغزٌ كبير
Just how did the killer manage to...
...كيف تمكّن الفاعل من
Come to think of it,
،بالمناسبة
why did the killer use the projector to light up the body?
لمَ استعمل القاتل جهاز العرض لتسليط الضوء على الجثّة؟
Was it just to recreate the last scene of the movie?
أكان لإعادة رسم المشهد الأخير من الفيلم فحسب؟
What's that?
ما هذا؟
Tape? What's it doing here?
شريط لاصق؟ لمَ يوجد هنا؟
This is...
...إنّه
That's it! I know the real reason why the killer lit up the body!
عرفته! هذا هو السبب الحقيقيّ !لتسليط الفاعل الضوء على الجثّة
Now, I see the truth behind this case!
!أرى حقيقة هذه القضيّة الآن
Dammit! There's no secret passage!
!تبّاً! لا معبر سرّي
Hamura-san! Ma'am! Doi-san!
!هامورا-سان! سيّدتي! دوري-سان
Don't tell me there's a real vampire among you!
!أيمكن أنّ هناك مصّاص دماء حقيقيّ بينكم؟
A vampire would be able to fly to the study room and back!
!يمكن لمصّاص الدماء الطيران للمكتب ثمّ العودة
Dear me. You appear to be exhausted, Mori-san.
يا إلهي، يبدو أنّ الإرهاق غلبك يا موري-سان
Take a nice nap and leave the rest to me, old man!
دع الباقي لي يا عمّ واسترح قليلاً
Here we go again...
...ها هي مُجدداً
Let's return to our rooms, too.
لنرجع لغرفنا بدورنا
Not so fast!
انتظروا
I was merely joking before. Now, it's time to get down to business.
كنتُ أمزح فحسب قبل قليل، الآن سندخل صلب الموضوع
Down to business?
صلب الموضوع؟
Are you suggesting you've discovered the truth to this incident?
أتقصد أنّك اكتشفت حقيقة القضيّة؟
Of course I am.
بالطبع
Really?!
حقّاً؟
Yes. All of it.
أجل، فهمت كلّ شيء
Let us hear your theory then, Mori-san.
أسمعنا استنتاجاتك إذاً يا موري-سان
First, the wooden stake used as the murder weapon.
أوّلاً، الوتد الخشبيّ المُستعمل في الجريمة
I thought only Hamura-san could have taken the stake,
ظننتُ أنّ هامورا-سان كان الوحيد القادر على أخذه
but actually, anyone could have stolen it from outside!
لكن كان يمكن لأيّ أحد سرقته من الخارج في الواقع
From outside?
من الخارج؟
There wasn't a single footstep in the snow outside, you know.
لم تكن هناك أيّ آثار أقدام على الثلج خارجاً
There were no footprints because the killer walked through the air.
لم تكن هناك آثار أقدام لأنّ القاتل مشى على الهواء
Walked through the air?
مشى على الهواء؟
Is this another of your jokes?
أهذه تتمّة لمزحتك؟
Were you aware that the window by the entrance hall is as high up
...أكنتم تعرفون أنّ النافذة عند ردهة المدخل
as the roof above the collection room window?
هي بارتفاع السطح فوق نافذة غرفة المقتنيات تقريباً؟
The killer used that fact to make a bridge...
استغلّ القاتل ذلك لصنع جسر
using a ladder.
باستعمال سلّم
A ladder?
سلّم؟
Yes.
أجل
Walking across it, the killer could get to the collection room window
بالمشي عليه، يمكن للقاتل الوصول لنافذة غرفة المقتنيات
without leaving any footsteps.
دون ترك أيّ آثار أقدام
As proof, there are ladder marks on the snow on the roof.
والدليل على ذلك هي آثار السلّم على الثلج فوق السطح
But, the windows were locked...
...لكن كانت النوافذ مقفلة
They could easily be opened with a simple little trick.
يمكن فتحها بحيلة بسيطة
By sticking the twig piece Conan found
بوضع طرف الغصين الذي وجده كونان
between the ventilation window's stopper and the glass.
بين سدّادة نافذة التهوية والزجاج
This way, the stopper will look like it's set,
،عندها سيبدو أنّ السدّادة مغلقة
but the window can still be opened freely.
لكن يمكن فتح النافذة بحريّة
The killer stole the stake from there.
سرق القاتل الوتد من هناك
Afterward, simply closing the window would make the stopper lock.
وبعدها، إغلاقه للنافذة عند المغادرة كفيل بقفل السدّادة آلياً
But, Mori-san! The stake was two meters from that window!
لكن يا موري-سان، كان الوتد يبعد !مترين عن النافذة
The killer used a tree pruner.
استعمل القاتل مقلّم تشذيب
You used one this afternoon, Tadokoro-san.
ألم تكن تستعمل واحداً ظهيرة اليوم يا تادوكورو-سان؟
There are attachments for those for picking fruit.
توجد لها ملحقات خاصّة لاقتطاف الفواكه
The killer attached one and stuck it through the ventilation window
ربطها القاتل وأدخلها عبر نافذة التهوية
to steal the stake.
وسرق الوتد
Using this method, anyone could have obtained the stake.
باستعمال هذه الطريقة، كان ممكناً لأيّ أحد أخذ الوتد
You can't be serious...
...لا يُعقل
But, Mori-san, how did the person go to the study and back?
لكن يا موري-سان، كيف ذهب الفاعل ورجع من المكتب؟
Simple, by crossing the corridor.
ذلك بسيط، عبر الممرّ
What are you talking about? That's absolute nonsense.
هذا الذي لديك لتقوله؟ يا للسخافة
Is it?
حقّاً؟
Isn't it much more logical than having the killer fly through the air?
أليس منطقياً أكثر من طيران الفاعل في الهواء؟
You were in the living room, too. You know no one used the corridor.
،كنتَ في غرفة المعيشة بدورك فتعي أنّه لم يستعمل أحدٌ الممرّ
Oh, but one person did.
بل يوجد شخص
Yes. The killer...
...صحيح، القاتل
was you, Tadokoro Toshiya-san!
!هو أنت يا تادوكورو توشيا-سان
Tadokoro-kun?
تادوكورو-كن؟
T-That can't be!
!لـ-لا يمكن
W-What are you talking about?!
ما-ما الذي تقوله؟
The stake was still in the collection room when I went to the study!
كان الوتد لا يزال في غرفة المقتنيات !عندما ذهبتُ للمكتب
Isn't that right?!
أليس ذلك صحيحاً؟
That's true, Dad!
!صحيح يا أبي
Ran, what you two saw was an elaborately-made fake.
ران، ما رأيتماه كان نسخةً مزيّفة بإتقان
A fake?!
مزيّفة؟
Yes.
أجل
When Tadokoro-san went to get the film, he invited you and Conan
عندما ذهب تادوكورو-سان لجلب الفيلم، دعاكِ وكونان
and showed you the stake, so you would confirm it had been there.
وأراكما الوتد المزيّف كي تؤكدّا على وجوده في الغرفة لاحقاً
Then, after killing Mr. Dorakura with the real stake,
تالياً، بعد قتله السيّد دوراكورا بالوتد الحقيقيّ
which he had hidden in the study in advance,
،الذي أخفاه في المكتب سلفاً
he pretended to check all the locks and stole the fake stake.
تظاهر بالذهاب للتحقّق من الأقفال وسرق الوتد المزيّف
But, Mori-san. Do you have proof the stake was a fake?
لكن يا موري-سان، ألديك دليل على كون ذاك الوتد مزيّفاً؟
What's this?
ما هذا؟
This turned up after I instructed Conan to look through the storeroom.
وجدناه بعدما طلبتُ من كونان البحث في المخزن
Yes, it's very well-made.
إنّه مصنوع بإتقان حقّاً
Was the fake blood added using oil paint?
هل أُضيف الدمّ المزيّف بطلاء زيتيّ؟
His wife does oil painting, so it would've been easy to get the paint.
،تهوى زوجته الرسم بالطلاء الزيتيّ فكان الحصول على الطلاء سهلاً
Tadokoro-kun...
...تادوكورو-كن
Mori-san. Even if he did use the corridor to reach the study,
،موري-سان، حتّى لو استعمل الممرّ للوصول للمكتب
how did he get inside?
كيف خرج؟
It was locked from the inside, so he couldn't have gone out the door.
كان المكتب مقفلاً من الداخل، فلم يستعمله عند الخروج
And if he left through the window, how did he return to the corridor?
وإذا غادر من النافذة، فكيف رجع للممرّ؟
There were no other footprints, except those in front of the window.
لم تكن هناك آثار أقدام إلّا أمام النافذة
The open window and the trampled snow were simply a red herring.
كانت النافذة المفتوحة والآثار الثلجيّة مجرّد تزييف
Tadokoro-san entered and exited through the door.
دخل تادوكورو-سان من الباب، وخرج منه
Then how could I have locked it from the outside?!
كيف أقفلتُ الباب من الخارج إذاً؟
Locking the door is no problem at all...
إقفال الباب ليس مشكلةً البتّة
if you use that projector, that is!
ذلك إذا استعملت جهاز العرض هناك
Projector?
جهاز العرض؟
W-What are you talking about? How could a projector do that?
...ما-ما الذي تقوله؟ كيف يمكن بجهاز العرض
Tadokoro-san, I've figured it all out, you know...
تادوكورو-سان، اكتشفتُ كلّ شيء
Including why you lit up the body.
بالإضافة لسبب تسليطك الضوء على الجثّة
Wasn't it to recreate the last scene of the movie?!
ألم يكن لإعادة رسم المشهد الأخير من الفيلم؟
No, it wasn't.
كلا
The body was lit up to camouflage the real reason
تمّ تسليط الضوء على الجثّة لإخفاء السبب الحقيقيّ
for moving the projector!
!لتحريك جهاز العرض
The real reason?
السبب الحقيقيّ؟
For this trick to work,
،لنجاح هذه الحيلة
it was absolutely vital to move the projector in front of the door.
لا بدّ من تحريك جهاز العرض ليكون أمام الباب تماماً
But, the trick would be obvious if only the projector were moved.
لكن ستكون الحيلة واضحة إذا تمّ تحريك جهاز العرض
So, by lighting up the body as a bit of an informed performance,
لذا، بتسليطه للضوء على الجثّة كجزءٍ من عرض سينمائي
our attention was diverted.
تمكّن من تشتيت انتباهنا
I'll now reenact this trick I speak of.
سأستعرض تلك الحيلة أمامكم الآن
Ran. Lend me a hand.
ران، ساعديني
Yes! Okay!
!أجل
First, pull about five meters of film from the reel.
أوّلاً، اسحبي قرابة 5 أمتار من الفيلم من البكرة
Right!
!حسناً
Next, stick a piece of tape on the end of the film.
تالياً، الصقي شريطاً لاصقاً بطرف الفيلم
After that, throw the film over the blackout curtain rail by the door,
بعدها، ارمي الفيلم فوق عارضة الستارة القاتمة أمام الباب
and attach it to the lock on the door.
واربطيه بقفل الباب
All done, Dad!
انتهيتُ يا أبي
Now everything is set.
كلّ شيءٍ جاهز الآن
Ran. Start the projector.
ران، شغّلي جهاز العرض
Right!
!حاضر
This is how Tadokoro-san locked the door.
هكذا أقفل تادوكورو-سان الباب
But, unfortunately for him, as the film was being pulled in,
،لكن لسوء حظّه، بينما كان الفيلم يُسحب
the piece of tape caught on the curtain rail and remained there.
علق جزءٌ من الشريط اللاصق بعارضة الستائر وبقي عليها
On the piece of tape are small, square marks... from perforations.
توجد على ذاك الجزء آثار مربّعة صغيرة وتُدعى بالثقوب التسلسلية
The square holes in the film, in other words.
أي أنّها الثقوب المربّعة في الفيلم
Tadokoro-san, can you give any other explanation
تادوكورو-سان، أيمكنك إعطاء تفسير آخر
as to why that perforation-marked tape was stuck on the curtain rail?
لالتصاق ذاك الشريط بالثقوب التسلسلية على عارضة الستائر؟
W-Well...
...ذ-ذلك
I think it's about time you tell us the truth.
أظنّ وقت البوح بالحقيقة قد حان
You already confessed you were the killer when the body was found.
فقد اعترفت بنفسك أنّك القاتل عندما تمّ العثور على الجثّة
At the time, you said you could hear the projector.
قلتَ وقتها أنّ بإمكانك سماع صوت جهاز العرض
Don't you find that strange?
أليس ذلك غريباً؟
The door had airtight, sound-proof rubber sealing.
كان لذاك الباب حاجز مطّاطي مانع للصوت
How could you hear what was happening inside?
كيف استطعتَ سماع ما بالداخل؟
You knew that the projector was on inside.
كنتَ تعرف أنّ جهاز العرض كان يعمل في الداخل
Or, shall we see if the projector is audible behind the closed door?
أم نختبر إذا كان صوته مسموعاً وراء الباب المغلق؟
I... killed him.
أنا... قتلتُه
Tadokoro-san...
...تادوكورو-سان
But why would you kill Dorakura-san?! What about your sister?!
!لكن لمَ؟
My sister... Kaori... has been dead for a year now...
...شقيقتي
That can't be...
...لا يمكن
Dorakura never gave Kaori real medical treatment.
لم يقدّم دوراكورا أيّ عناية طبيّة فعليّة لكاوري
He paid off her doctor so she would get neither better nor worse.
رشى طبيبها بحيث تتلقّى العلاج الأدنى فلا تتحسّن حالتها أو تسوء
Just to keep Kaori hospitalized longer.
لإطالة إبقاء كاوري في المشفى فقط
But, then her condition suddenly took a turn for the worse, and she...
...لكن تدهورت صحّتها فجأةً، ثمّ
I only found out about this one month ago.
اكتشفتُ ذلك قبل شهرٍ فقط
Dorakura kept my sister's death secret the entire time!
!أخفى دوراكورا وفاة أختي طوال هذا الوقت
I believed his lie about sending her to a better hospital in America...
صدّقت كذبته بإرساله لها لمشفى أفضل في أمريكا
But, one month ago...
...لكن، قبل شهر
Kaori's nurse couldn't bear it anymore and secretly came to tell me.
لم تستطع الممرضة المشرفة على كاوري الاحتمال وأتت لإخباري سرّاً
She said Kaori deliriously cried my name over and over as she died...
قالت أنّها ماتت وهي تتمتم باسمي مراراً
If she had, had real treatment...
...لو تلقّت علاجاً مناسباً
If she had had real treatment, that never would've happened!
!لو تلقّت علاجاً مناسباً لما حصل ذلك
Dorakura murdered Kaori!
!دوراكورا قتلَ كاوري
That's why... That's why I...
...لذا... لذا قمتُ بـ
They say a vampire's bite can turn a normal person into a vampire.
يُقال أنّ عضّة مصّاص الدماء تحوّل الإنسان لمصّاص دماء بدوره
Unknowingly, Tadokoro-san might have become a vampire himself.
لعلّ تادوكورو-سان تحوّل لمصّاص دماء ...دون أن يعي
A vampire known as a murderer...
مصّاص دماء يُعرف بالقاتل
Franken Manor?!
قصر فرانكين؟
Yeah. It belongs to Furano Kenzo, an engineering professor.
أجل، يخصّ بروفسوراً هندسيّاً يُدعى فورانو كينزو
Apparently, he conducts strange experiments every night and--
...يبدو أنّه يجري تجارباً غريبة كلّ ليلة و
This time it's Frankenstein...
هذه المرّة فرانكنشتاين
Mr. Shiraki!
!الـ-السيّد شيراكي
Something's not right! What could it be?!
هناك شيءٌ غريب في هذه الزهرة... ما هو؟
Wait a minute!
!انتظر
If Okano Rika-san is the killer, who will she go after next?!
،لو كانت أوكانو ريكا-سان هي الفاعلة فمن ستستهدف تالياً؟
This is bad! Who is she trying to kill?!
من؟ من الذي تستهدفه؟
Who is it?! I'm not gonna make it in time!
!لا جدوى! لن أصل في الوقت
On the next Conan: "The Flower Scent Murder Case."
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Ice.
جليد
Next episode fits me perfectly. Smells like flowers.
...في الحلقة القادمة أزهار زكيّة تطابقني
Sometimes pretty flowers have thorns.
قد تمتلك الأزهار الجميلة أشواكاً